ARISE; Records apap392
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
ARISE Records
1969-1970
1999
2002-2003
2007
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
apap392
.6 cubic ft.
This collection contains a small amount of materials documenting the day-to-day activities of ARISE (A Regional Initiative Supporting Empowerment) primarily during 2002-2003 as well as related research material.
Historical Note
ARISE (A Regional Initiative Supporting Empowerment) was an organization based in New York's Capital Region. Members included people from various faith-based congregations, community groups, activist organizations, and neighborhood associations. ARISE sought to implement social, political, and economic change in the Capital Region. Topics of concern and interest to the group included environmental preservation due to the onset of development of the region in the 2000s. Established in 1997 as a coalition of Schenectady County churches and community organizations, ARISE subsequently expanded into the counties of Albany, Rensselaer, and Saratoga and was active in the Capital Region until the 2010s. The donor of the records, Lynne Jackson, was active in ARISE communication and planning from 2002-2003, with some evidence of involvement in 2007.
Content Description
This collection contains records collected by one-time ARISE member Lynne Jackson related to event planning, email correspondence, meeting minutes, notes, attendance lists, and invite lists for the organization, as well as related research materials about urban sprawl, technology campus development, economic development, affordable housing, and other topics. It also includes newsletters, conference materials, pamphlets, and other handouts from organizations other than ARISE that shared similar goals or initiatives.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is arranged chronologically. There are no series. The archivist maintained the donor's approximate chronological organization of records while maintaining separate folders for select non-ARISE workshops and events in the collection.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Lynne Jackson donated all materials in this collection to the M.E. Grenandner Department of Special Collections and Archives in April 2021.
Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted.
ARISE (A Regional Initiative Supporting Empowerment); Social Activists and Public Advocates; Power (social sciences) -- New York (State); Cities and towns--Growth; Sustainable urban development
- Clippings and Research, 1969-1970; 2002-2003; Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Smart Growth: An Idea Whose Time Has Come for New York State, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Audubon New York Important Bird Areas Program Information, 2002 March; Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Meeting Agendas, Correspondence, and Notes, 2002 June-2002 December; Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Contact Information and Attendance Lists, 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Rosa House Peace Community, The Sower Winter Newsletter, 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- March 14 Regional Forum Planning Meeting Agendas, Correspondence, and Notes, 2003 January; Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Draft Generic Impact Statement, Luther Forest Technology Campus (1 of 2), 2003 January-2003 March (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Draft Generic Impact Statement, Luther Forest Technology Campus (2 of 2), 2003 January-2003 March (Box 1, Folder 9)
- March 14 Regional Forum Planning Meeting Agendas, Correspondence, and Notes, 2003 February; Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- ARISE News Articles and Related Correspondence, 2003 March (Box 1, Folder 11)
- March 14 Regional Forum Planning Meeting Agendas, Correspondence, and Notes, 2003 March; Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Regional Forum Mailing Notes, 2003 April (Box 1, Folder 13)
- June 13 Regional Forum Planning Meeting Agendas, Correspondence, and Notes, 2003 April; Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
- June 13 Regional Forum Planning Meeting Agendas, Correspondence, and Notes, 2003 May-2003 June; Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
- ARISE Pamphlet and 3rd Annual Public Meeting Save the Date, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- June 19, 2003 Gun Violence in the Capital Region Community Workshop (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Community Pamphlets, 2003; Undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Everyday Tips to Help Reduce CO2 Emissions and Save Money, 2003; Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
- ARISE Program Book and Annual Report, 2007 March (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Why New York Needs an Independent Public Defense Commission, 2007 July (Box 2, Folder 5)
- ARISE 7th annual Action Meeting, 2007 October (Box 2, Folder 6)
- ARISE Declaration of Independence, Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
- CDTC's 10 Adopted Strategies and 43 Adopted Actions, Undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Economic Development Workshop, Undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Inner City Redevelopment and Land Use and Planning Notes, Undated (Box 2, Folder 10)